So, let us discuss about the KPA hooking the methods we have that was the one another
we are going to see the detour, KPA hooking in this video ok.
So, this is one of this is one of really a good example and a good method to bypass
situations and even the EDRs and antivir software will be also using this APA is to do some
task in the machine.
Let me explain what is a detour first ok.
So, detour is one of our technique that was introduced by the Microsoft.
So, this is specially designed for intercepting the functions called and redirecting
it to the custom functions ok.
So, basically let us say an example of let me give a small example here there is a source
function and let us think about you know think about your applications your application
is going to save a file by calling the save file of APA function.
So, once the source function the source function is this the source function needs
to save some file ok.
So, the source function was calling a save file of function and it was executed by the
target function ok.
So, once the save file has been once the file has been saved this was redirected to the
source function again ok let us take an example you are downloading something from Google
Chrome or some browser application.
So, your browser application called save file that is a source function and the target
function will be it was saved a file it was executed the save file of and saved a file
in the hot hot days.
So, once the file gets saved successfully it was redirecting again to the source function
ok again to the source function what needs to be what needs to execute another other
ok.
So, this is invocation without interception.
So, this is something like a functions file right we are calling a function save file
of and we are doing something and we are again returning to the source function ok.
So, let us take about the detour function, so let us draw in the image so let us consider
a detour.
So, there is a source function and we have a target here.
So, what we are doing so once the program once the once the source function called the
target function.
So, we are saying we are giving some special instructions, special instruction to the target
function like do not execute the target function now so move to the detour ok, just jump
to the detour function and execute the custom code, execute the code the detour and then
move to the target function ok.
So, let me give an example.
So, here we designed a code so here you can see a simple C++ program here and I just
given implemented a detour function so here you can see detour transaction begin off.
So, what we are doing here ok.
So, once the program executing the main function so the next thing will be attached the
detour ok.
So, once the function source function gets called this was redirected to the main function
charge once it was redirected to the detour function ok.
So, now we are telling the telling our program so what custom code present under the detour
function.
So, what detour was saying so executes that, executes that and redirected and redirect towards
the trampoline function ok.
So, we are temporarily skipping the target functions to execute instead of target functions
our program executes the detour of functions.
So, once the detour functions executed so our target memory address ok our target function
memory address will be saved under the trampoline function and once the detour functions
executes it is redirected to the trampoline functions and trampoline function has our memory
address of a target function and it redirected to the total function and executes that ok.
So, basically in our code what we are doing so we are just use the detour transaction
begin off detour function and we have attached the function real message and my message
box ok.
So, this will be redirected towards the hook function my message box W of and it will execute
this custom hook to function ok.
We given the detour attach of the my message box of function ok and we are saved the real
message in the trampoline function and we executing the hook function the contact of the
hook function and so once the custom hook function gets executes it redirect towards the original
function ok.
Let me explain this code in a brief ok.
So, let me will start from the beginning of the code how the code has been in design let
me tell you some interesting factor.
So, now we have the first line this is the library thing so let us keep that ok.
We are declare a pointer for a real message box W ok this is the real message message
box hello world this is the normal thing ok.
This is the one this needs to be print once we execute the programming our machine ok.
But you can you can understand what it will do when one one see executes the program ok.
Let us go to the program so this is the real message W of function pointer and we just
saved the memory address of message box W into the pointer L message box W ok.
So, in this line we are just we are just taking a photocopy copy of message box W memory
address and we are sending it into the real message box W to use it later ok.
So, this line is called a trampoline function I already I said so this trampoline function
has the target function memory address.
So, once the custom function once the custom detour function has been execute executed so
after the next up will be it will be moving towards the trampoline function so the trampoline
function contains the memory address of a target function so then it will be executing
the core right.
So, let us move to the program to the next line and to be how few of the custom detour
function so here you can find the detour function in the message box W of or it may have
some water yep so my message box W of function so in in in my message box W of function
so I have I have written some of some of the messages like who can message W called original
text this message was intercepted by the data so we execute the program and we can understand
what what will happen here ok.
So, this is the beginning of the detour so we are just programming this is like I just
said a special function we are giving a giving to our program right we are redirecting our
source function to the detour function right so that say we have called inside the detour
function in the int main of we just redirect to the detour function so this is the
beginning of the detour and and so this is the message we need to print this is the
word and message ok we need to print it so generally but let us see how our program is
going to execute this one ok. Let us see I have a program and here let me execute the
code.exe and here you can see how my how my program executed ok. So, so once I W picked
on the application so here you can see the detour example the message was intercepted by
the detours so this get this get executed right. So, who can message us ok right and
the who ok right here you can find it just printed a who can message and so after so
this will be executed first then what it will do it will execute the detour example
this small console. So, once the console get executed after that the original text will
be get printed ok we are just we are just tampering the function and we are executing
our custom code we are hiding our custom code and basically we are hiding our custom code
and we are executing ok. So, now this is called as the API hooking we are hook the message
box W API and instead of executing message box W functions we are executing the detour
my message box W of function and we are printing the output ok.
So, this will be this is called as the detour function. So, you have an you have an
question. So, why Microsoft introduced a detour function ok. Let us see an example I already
said some of the programmers who left the organization and that program needs to get
some update like that the application only have a only have a capability to save a file
but the developer left in between from the company. So, now the code was not visible
to everyone. So, the application application. So, now there is a different developer
for working and he needs to and she needs to update some kind of features like deleting
the contents modifying the contents. So, at that time you can use the detour functions
and you can put the APIs and you can execute the program right. So, this is this is why
Microsoft introduced for a rename purpose ok. The areas and antivirus software simply are
so using this or detour set a functions to remove the threat files from the machines ok.
So, in the cybersecurity threat type of perspective inside the custom group to functions
we are hiding our malicious code or hiding our malicious EA executables inside the custom
group functions and we are executing that ok. So, this is this one of the way we can
easily hide the antivirus software and EDR programs before by using the API hooking ok.
So, instead of calling original message box W of API functions we implemented the detour
and we have called the called the my message box W one of the custom hook functions and
we are we executed our code right. So, this method has been implemented in lot of
malware like we will key lovers 2 monitor the keyboard strokes, spyware, Trojan was etcetera
sorry, fibers and few kind of malware. So, this is one of powerful method to bypass the
EDR technique ok. This is a simple example when you can do do a more by extending this
program so, you people have better idea and so, once you complete the course you can develop
develop a new malware study by using the hooking technique.
So, I hope you have enjoyed this video and you have a clear understanding about what is
the detour and how detour API hooking will work. So, we can hop off from this video and
we will connect guys in the next video see you have a sorry and one more thing. So, once
we execute the detour things we need to we need to do the detas exceed the detas we have
attached the custom hook functions as well as the original message memory address. So, once
everything has been done we need to detas the hook before exit ok. So, thank you for
watching this video, we will see you guys in the next video bye bye.